Stephanie Knight

602.622.1650 stephanie@sknight.co

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a versatile and energetic finance professional with experience in consulting, corporate finance, and a startup. I excel at problem solving in fast-paced work environments while adhering to strict deadlines. In each of my prior positions I produced and presented relevant, detailed, and polished analyses to assist management with strategic decisions. I have maintained high standards of accuracy and integrity when handling confidential business and financial information. I continually challenge myself by learning new software and analytics tools or by improving my existing technical skills.

EDUCATION

B.S. Economics and B.A. Mathematics with French Minor, magna cum laude Arizona State University

December 2010

Tempe, AZ

Honors: ASU President's Scholar

Barrett Honors College Graduate
Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society Member

Activities: Research Experience for Undergraduates Program, ASU Department of Mathematics, Tempe, AZ

2008 Triumvirate Model Parliament, North American Forum on Integration, Montreal, QC, Canada

Thesis: Investing in the Future: An Econometric Analysis of Research and Development Investment in the

U.S. Oil and Gas Industry, Department of Economics and Barrett Honors College, Tempe, AZ

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Financial Analyst

Ecomom

September 2012 - January 2013

Las Vegas, NV

- Independently developed and managed the financial model for an e-commerce startup
- Worked with the CEO and Controller to develop financial forecasts and department budgets
- Analyzed financial information to assist the Controller in identifying important revenue and expense trends
- Worked with multiple departments to optimize operations and operational expenses
- Partnered with multiple departments to lead the development of detailed analyses and reports that improved the accuracy and efficiency of strategic decision-making
 - Developed a pro forma model for the Marketing department to evaluate potential marketing programs
 - Performed statistical analyses of sales data for the Finance, Marketing, and Operations departments
 - Performed ad hoc analyses, such as analyses of website visitor behavior using Google Analytics
- Prepared presentation materials for the 2012 Board of Directors meeting

Financial and Operations Analyst Downtown Project, VegasTech.com Las Vegas, NV

May 2012 - September 2012

- Created financial models and budgets for VegasTech business entities, including a co-working business, a hacker space, a meeting venue, and a retail space
 - Researched operating and capital expenses to create accurate financial projections
 - Modeled, analyzed, and presented financial scenarios based upon revenue and expense assumptions
- Independently developed recommendations for operational decisions based upon analyses of the potential financial implications for the businesses
- Coordinated effective collaboration between VegasTech and multiple external stakeholders during the development and construction phases of the businesses

Analyst 2011 - 2012

Analysis Group

Dallas, TX

- Provided economic modeling, financial analysis, and damages quantification in complex commercial litigation

- Conducted detailed data analyses, both independent and directed
- Assisted in formulating econometric models to assess damages in an international anti-trust dispute
- Conducted lost sales and reasonable royalty analyses for intellectual property and trade secret litigation
- Assisted in the preparation of expert reports for depositions and trials
 - Conducted company and market research to develop industry evaluations for subsequent analyses
 - Wrote significant sections of expert reports
 - Critiqued the analyses of opposing experts
 - Assisted in directing the case work of fellow Analysts
- Trained newly hired employees and mentored a newly hired Analyst

Financial Analyst Intern

2010 - 2011

ON Semiconductor Corp., Automotive and Power Group and Standard Products Group Phoenix, AZ

- Completed numerous daily, weekly, and monthly financial reports for two business units
 - Analyzed financial information of a publicly traded company
 - Identified and helped to resolve errors in financial queries and reports
 - Maintained high standards of accuracy and confidentiality
- Presented a competitive analysis project to the Automotive and Power Group, which was subsequently presented by senior management at the 2010 Board of Directors meeting
 - Created and analyzed a database of financial metrics with quantitative and visual statistical methods
 - Evaluated ON's financial performance as compared to that of its primary market competitors

Student Researcher 2007 - 2009

Arizona State University Department of Mathematics, Research Experience for Undergraduates Program Tempe, AZ

- Worked with professors and students on bio-economic and institutional analysis research projects
 - Explored ecological issues and common pool resource (CPR) systems using institutional analysis
 - Constructed mathematical models of CPR systems and used applied mathematical analysis to examine dynamics of the models

Research Assistant 2006 - 2007

Arizona State University W. P. Carey School of Business, JPMorgan Chase Economic Outlook Center Tempe, AZ

- Worked alongside research economists to produce periodical publications and special research projects
 - Researched and summarized salient macroeconomic data and relevant academic papers for economists
 - Used software programs EViews and SAS to analyze and produce slides of economic data
- Managed over 200 contacts for a monthly golf industry survey
 - Recorded and reported the financial data of each golf course with accuracy
 - Maintained strict standards of confidentiality

SKILLS

Software: Microsoft Access, Excel, and PowerPoint (proficient); Google Analytics (familiar); enterprise software Hyperion, Magento, OMX, and QuickBooks (familiar); statistical software EViews, R, and Stata (prior experience) **Languages**: English (native), French (intermediate speaking ability, advanced reading ability)